Hello everyone, today we are going to talk about a super important skill
大家好，今天我們要談論一項超級重要的技能
How to communicate with your AI colleagues
如何與你的 AI 同事溝通
That's right, you didn't hear wrong, it's a colleague
沒錯，你沒有聽錯，是同事
Learn to give instructions is equivalent to mastering the key to working with this new partner
學會給出指示相當於掌握了與這個新夥伴工作的鑰匙
Have you ever had this experience
你有過這種經歷嗎
You think you've made it very clear
你認為你已經說得非常清楚了
But that AI assistant
但那個 AI 助手
I don't seem to understand what you're saying
似乎不理解你在說什麼
It's really a little crazy, right?
真的有點令人抓狂，對吧？
Don't worry, this is normal
別擔心，這很正常
A lot of people are like you
很多人和你一樣
What about the solution
那解決方案是什麼呢
In fact, it's as expected
其實就像你想的那樣
You imagine it as a new colleague who just reported
把它想像成一位剛剛入職的新同事
He is super active and full of enthusiasm
他超級積極主動，充滿熱情
I want to do things well
想把事情做好
But he needs you to give him a very clear direction
但他需要你給他非常清晰的方向
As long as you remember this core concept
只要你記住這個核心概念
All the skills we're going to talk about later today
我們今天稍後要談的所有技能
You will be able to communicate immediately
你就能立刻進行有效溝通
Okay, let's get started
好的，讓我們開始吧
Imagine today is your first day of work as an AI colleague
想像今天是你作為 AI 同事的第一天上班
We will help him do a newbie training
我們將幫助他進行新手培訓
Make sure we can work smoothly from the first day
確保我們從第一天就能順利合作
OK, you may have heard a very powerful word
好的，你可能聽過一個非常厲害的詞
It's called prompt engineering
叫做 prompt engineering（提示詞工程）
Wow, it sounds like it's going to be written as a word
哇，聽起來好像要寫成一個詞
It's complicated, right?
很複雜，對吧？
But wait
但等等
In fact, what we are talking about today is more like an effective communication skill
其實我們今天談論的更像是一種有效的溝通技能
This really has nothing to do with writing
這真的和寫作無關
The point is how you clearly and instinctively express your thoughts
重點是你如何清晰和直觀地表達你的想法
It's exactly the same as you communicate with real people
這和你與真人溝通完全一樣
Okay, next we're going to take a look at six super basic skills step by step
好的，接下來我們將逐步看六項超基礎的技能
Really, as long as you master these six points
真的，只要你掌握這六點
You will find that your communication quality with AI
你就會發現你與 AI 的溝通質量
Wow, it's going to be a leap forward
哇，將會有飛躍性的提升
Okay, let's get into the main topic
好的，讓我們進入主題
This is like you want to handle the first project for that new colleague
這就像你想給那位新同事處理第一個項目
The first step is to give a super clear task report
第一步是給出一份超級清晰的任務說明
The first skill is also the most important
第一個技能也是最重要的
Be sure to give the situation and purpose
一定要說明情況和目的
You see, this comparison is super obvious
你看，這個對比非常明顯
On the left, if you only say to AI
左邊，如果你只是對AI說
Hey, tell me about climate change
嘿，告訴我關於氣候變遷的事
Oh my god, the scope is so big
天哪，範圍太大了
He can only guess what you want to know
它只能猜測你想知道什麼
But look at the right
但看看右邊
The instructions are completely different
指令完全不同
He said I was preparing for a job interview for agricultural research in Indonesia
他說我在為印尼農業研究的工作面試做準備
And then the specific requirements
然後是具體的要求
Climate change has three main effects on tropical agriculture
氣候變遷對熱帶農業有三個主要影響
You see, when you give this
你看，當你提供這些
Why and where to use the background information
為什麼以及在哪裡使用背景信息
The answer given by AI will be really accurate
AI給出的答案會非常準確
And then the second skill
然後是第二個技能
Define a role for AI
為AI定義一個角色
This method is really, really super useful
這種方法真的、真的非常有用
We call it the human color hint
我們稱之為人設提示
You can directly specify that AI plays a certain expert
你可以直接指定AI扮演某位專家
For example, you tell him
例如，你告訴它
Please play an experienced science teacher
請扮演一位經驗豐富的科學老師
Then use a smart 10-year-old child
然後用聰明的10歲小孩
Also understand the method
也理解的方式
Explain to me how the rainbow is formed
向我解釋彩虹是如何形成的
Wow, you set it up like this
哇，你這樣設置
The tone, use of words and the depth of explanation given by AI
AI提供的語氣、措辭和解釋深度
Will be completely different
會完全不同
Become super in place
變得非常恰當
OK, we've set up the background and role
好的，我們設置了背景和角色
What about the next step
下一步呢
Of course, you have to tell him very specifically
當然，你必須很具體地告訴它
The finished product you want
你想要的最終產品
That is, what does the deliverable look like
也就是說，交付物看起來像什麼
The third skill
第三個技能
Do it directly for him
直接為它展示
Don't just say it
不要只是說
Well, as the saying goes, the voice is more important than the words
嗯，正如俗話所說，示範勝於言語
Sometimes you give an example
有時候你給一個例子
It's really more than a thousand words
真的勝過千言萬語
This is called a few sample hint on a professional
這被稱為專業人士的少樣本提示
It sounds great
聽起來很棒
But the concept is very simple
但這個概念非常簡單
Just like this example on the screen
就像屏幕上的這個例子
You give him a sentence that is full of technical words before editing
你給它一個編輯前充滿技術詞彙的句子
Then give him a modified version
然後給它一個修改過的版本
AI just look
AI 只需要看看
Oh, so this is the style you want
哦，所以這就是你想要的風格
I'll learn it right away
我會立即學會
The fourth skill
第四個技巧
It is important to clearly specify the limit of output
清楚地指定輸出限制是很重要的
For example, you can't just tell him
例如，你不能只告訴它
Help me design a website
幫我設計一個網站
It's too blurry
這太模糊了
You have to give him specific conditions like this
你必須給它具體的條件，像這樣
For example, the guide list must be fixed on top
例如，導航列必須固定在頂部
The color should be the kind of sunset color
顏色應該是日落色那種
And there should be a dark and light color mode to switch
而且應該有深色和淺色模式可以切換
The clearer the frame you give
你給的框架越清楚
What he does
它做出來的
The more it will be the way you want
就越會是你想要的樣子
Okay, the fifth skill
好的，第五個技巧
Solve the complex tasks one by one
一個一個地解決複雜任務
This method is also very famous
這個方法也很有名
It's called a thought chain hint
它被稱為思維鏈提示
Don't just throw a big question to him
不要只是把一個大問題扔給它
Like helping me analyze the sales data of this season
像幫我分析本季的銷售數據
So he might miss the focus
這樣它可能會偏離重點
You can try to list your thinking process like this
你可以嘗試像這樣列出你的思考過程
The first step is to find the best product
第一步是找出最好的產品
The second step is to compare with the previous season
第二步是與上一季進行比較
The third step is to find out which trends are very special
第三步是找出哪些趨勢非常特別
The fourth step is to try to guess the reason
第四步是嘗試猜測原因
You see, when you take him step by step
你看，當你一步步引導它
He can follow your logic
它可以跟上你的邏輯
The analysis report of output will of course be more in-depth
輸出的分析報告當然會更深入
There are more regulations
還有更多規則
Okay, here we go
好的，我們來吧
Everyone must remember one key point
每個人都必須記住一個關鍵點
Working with AI
與 AI 合作
It's not a one-way guide that I say you do
這不是一種單向的指導，我說你做
It's more like a process of coming back and forth, constantly communicating, constantly optimizing
這更像是一個不斷往返、持續溝通、不斷優化的過程
This is also the fourth part we are going to enter
這也是我們即將進入的第四部分
Cooperation
協作
The sixth skill
第六個技能
This is an advanced method
這是一個進階方法
Is to ask him to think first
是要求它先思考
It's wonderful, right?
很妙，對吧？
You can add a sentence in front of your real instructions
你可以在實際指令前加一句話
Like before answering
像在回答之前
Please think about this question step by step
請逐步思考這個問題
Describe all kinds of factors and possible restrictions
描述各種因素和可能的限制
It's like you're telling your colleague
就像你在告訴你的同事
Don't rush to do it
不要急著去做
Take five minutes to think about the whole plan
花五分鐘思考整個計畫
You give him the space to think
你給了它思考的空間
The quality that is usually produced at the end will really be much better
最後通常產出的品質真的會好得多
Okay, we just talked about six skills, right?
好的，我們剛才談到了六個技能，對吧？
But if there is one of the most powerful and powerful
但如果有最強大、最有力的
What do you think will be the ultimate skill?
你認為終極技能會是什麼？
The answer is
答案是
Our secret weapon is
我們的祕密武器是
Please ask AI to help you
請要求 AI 幫助你
That's right
沒錯
When you are stuck and don't know how to give instructions
當你陷入困境，不知道如何下達指令
You just tell him honestly
你只需要誠實地告訴它
I'm not sure how to ask
我不確定該如何提問
To get the best result
才能得到最好的結果
You can help me
你能幫我嗎
Design a better hint
設計一個更好的提示
What will you do
你會做什麼
The moment you ask this question
在你提出這個問題的那一刻
AI uses an instruction tool
AI 使用指令工具
Immediately upgraded to your personal advisor and assistant
立即升級成你的個人顧問和助手
So the key is to constantly adjust and optimize
所以關鍵是不斷調整和優化
The first result is not perfect
第一個結果並不完美
That's super normal
那是非常正常的
You can try these methods
你可以試試這些方法
Tell him to give me three different styles of versions
告訴它給我三種不同風格的版本
Or help me change the form
或幫我改變形式
You can even challenge him and ask him
你甚至可以挑戰他，問他
How much confidence do you have in your answer?
你對你的答案有多大的信心？
Oh, by the way, there is a little skips
順便說一下，有個小技巧
If you feel that the conversation is too strong
如果你覺得對話過於強烈
Don't hesitate to start a new conversation directly
不要猶豫，直接開始新的對話
Sometimes the effect is better
有時效果會更好
Okay, let's sum it up
好的，讓我們總結一下
You will find
你會發現
What we learned today
我們今天學到的
It's not just some tips to give instructions
不僅僅是一些指令技巧
It's also a change of mentality
也是一種心態的改變
That is, how can we become
也就是說，我們如何才能成為
A better AI assistant
更好的 AI 助手
This summary table
這個總結表格
I think it's very well organized
我認為組織得非常好
You can take a look
你可以看一看
What to do
要做的事
Is to give a clear task description
就是給出清晰的任務描述
Provide a rich background
提供豐富的背景信息
Don't do anything
不要做的事
Just don't think that AI will read your mind
就是不要認為 AI 會讀心術
Don't give that kind of blurry instruction
不要給出那種模糊不清的指令
And please don't put a few
也請不要把幾個
Irrelevant questions
無關的問題
All mixed in the same dialogue
全部混在同一個對話中
It's easy to mess it up
那很容易搞砸
Finally, I want to leave a question
最後，我想留下一個問題
Let's go back and think about it
讓我們回過頭去思考
You see, the evolution of AI is so fast
你看，AI 的發展如此迅速
In the future, we really need to spend more effort
在未來，我們確實需要花費更多精力
To learn to adapt
來學習適應
Is it a machine or are we human beings?
是機器還是我們人類？
Maybe how to improve our own communication ability
也許如何提高我們自己的溝通能力
Is the ultimate key to truly grasp the era of human-machine cooperation in the future
才是真正掌握未來人機協作時代的終極鑰匙